In this demo, we'll be creating and utilizing some functions.
Once you're ready, fire up Visual Studio Code, and let's go.
Once Visual Studio Code loads navigate to your demo folder, we're on the functions demo,
so click on the functions folder here, and then finally, double click on functions.go.
Once that's loaded, you're ready to go.
So the first function we'll be creating is a function that doubles a number.
So we'll call it double, and it's going to take a single parameter,
and it's going to be an integer parameter, and it's going to also return an integer.
We're just going to return the number plus itself, that way we can double it.
We'll then create a second function name add, and that we're going to be adding two numbers together.
So we have a left hand side, a right hand side, and both are going to be integers.
Since we're using the same type integer for both left hand side and right hand side,
we don't need to specify it two times.
So we can just use a comma, and use int once, and both of these here will be integers.
The add function is going to be returning an integer, so let's return left hand side plus right hand side.
Next, we'll make a function called greet, and that's going to display a message.
This function has no input parameters and no output data, so we can just use parentheses with nothing in it.
And we'll just use a blank space right there.
In our greet function, we'll use the format package, and we'll do a print line,
hello from greet function.
We go down on our main function, we can start utilizing these functions we just created.
So the first function we'll use is the greet function.
To call the function, all we need to do is type the name of the function and our two parentheses.
The next function we'll use is the double function. So I'm going to create and assign a variable name dozen,
and we're going to take the double function, we'll double the number six,
and that'll give us 12, which is a dozen.
We'll need to print out this result, that way we can see that we get the correct number.
Next up, we'll create a baker's dozen, so a baker's dozen is 13.
So we'll use the add function, and we're going to add our dozen that we already have,
we'll add one to it, and we'll print that out as well.
So what we're doing here with the add function is we're adding the value of dozen and one.
Here in our double function, we're doubling six, which is 12, that'll get placed into dozen.
But we're then going to add the dozen from here, that's going to be 12,
and we'll add one to it, and this is going to place 13 into a baker's dozen.
So baker's dozen will have 13.
And finally, we're going to have both functions call at the same time, so we'll do
another baker's dozen, and that will be the result of add and double,
and then we'll print that out.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So here we're nesting functions, we have the add function, and the double function.
This double function is going to be called first, and we'll get a 12 back.
Once we have that 12, we'll take the 12 and the one,
add them together in this function, and then return a 13 into another baker's dozen variable.
Once you have all that in, let's save our work, and go hop into a terminal,
and see if we get the right answers.
To run this demo, we'll use gorun.slashdemo/functions.
And so here we have hello from read function, a dozen is 12,
a baker's dozen is 13, and another baker's dozen is also 13.
This concludes the demo on writing and utilizing functions.
I'll see you in the next presentation.